<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journey on Jon Gomez Blog</title>
    <link>https://jongomez.github.io/tags/journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journey on Jon Gomez Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 17:26:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jongomez.github.io/tags/journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Week 5/26</title>
      <link>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Week 5 of my wordpress theme journey. The website is up, but I still haven&amp;rsquo;t put anything in it. It&amp;rsquo;s just a dummy website for now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the content now for the past 3 weeks. I hope to make my first sale this month still. But it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be easy. I still have to set up my server&amp;rsquo;s database and write some articles. Only then will I be able to start selling themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s performance wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great. I gotta step up my game. Working 2 hours a day on the website isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. How can I stop being a lazy ass dude? Not sure. And I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of things. Most of these things failed, but there were some things that improved my productiviy, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visualizing the work to be done as a couple of dumbbells, waiting to be carried. I think this works for a couple of reasons, such as: the work is no longer boring, hard, and there&amp;rsquo;s no negative feelings associated with it. Work becomes just a healthy mental challenge: can you carry these dumbbells or not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking 10 minutes to think about my future self, or how my present self defined by my past self&amp;rsquo;s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotta find more things that work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Weeks 3/26 and 4/26</title>
      <link>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey3and4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey3and4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t make an update last week because I was too busy participating on the Data Science Bowl 2017 competition. I actually thought I could get into the top 10 and receive prize money. Even though I only had 1 week to work on the competition before it ended. Hahaha. Other than doing the kaggle competition, I was sick for a couple of days, had to work a little bit on my thesis&amp;hellip; and that was about it. These past 2 weeks I didn&amp;rsquo;t make any progress on my wordpress theme journey. Which is absolutely unacceptable. My priorities got mixed up somewhere along the line. The journey should always be number one. Screw everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have stopped for a while&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m not giving up. My journey continues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Week 2/26</title>
      <link>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2 weeks have passed. This second week was also a bad one. However, it was way better than the first week. Mainly because I worked way harder on my wordpress stuff. Which was nice. This increase in productivity was mainly due to something really stupid I did: I created a &amp;ldquo;default new tab page&amp;rdquo; on my browser, with some pictures of my parents, some motivational quotes and images. So everytime I opened up a new tab, I&amp;rsquo;d get a message from my parents, saying &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t waste your life ya fucking dummy&amp;rdquo;. As stupid as this sounds, I think it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also came up with what I believe to be a really good idea for an online business involving wordpress. In fact, I thought it was such a great idea that I threw out lot of the stuff I did on week 1, just to work on this new idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having done a lot of hard work, I constantly felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t working on the best things. For example, I spent around 1 hour trying to find a domain name. And after I found a good one, I kept going back trying to test other domains. Same thing with finding a wordpress theme for my site. But hey, at least now I&amp;rsquo;ve got a domain and a theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also did a little bit of work on my thesis, but not much. Not much progress on my weightloss sub-journey either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this upcoming 3rd week, I hope to focus more on my thesis. I also hope to work not only harder, but smarter. How am I going to work smarter? Here are a few suggestions for myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do a lot more planning. &amp;ldquo;Plans are useless, but planning is indispensable&amp;rdquo;, said Eisenhower (I think). Not sure if I agree with the &amp;ldquo;plans are useless&amp;rdquo; part, but I definitely agree that having a &amp;ldquo;planning&amp;rdquo; habit is more useful than just writing down plans on a piece of paper every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your mind wander (wonder?). Your basic/default state of mind is not a good one. This is a state of mind where any thought can take over your mind. Avoiding this state of mind is going to take effort, but ultimately will improve your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take breaks and meditate for about 5 to 10 minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to be easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably forget about all this in the morning. SEE YA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Week 1/26</title>
      <link>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This first week was not a good one. I only spent around 10 hours working on sales stuff. I could&amp;rsquo;ve done that in 1 day if I put my mind into it. These 10 hours were spent reading reading stuff, searching for niches, methods, and so on. I&amp;rsquo;m still going to focus on wordpress themes, but now I&amp;rsquo;ve decided not to start developing themes right away. I&amp;rsquo;ll just focus on selling existing themes, via affiliate programs. The envato market has an affiliate program I&amp;rsquo;d like to try out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I lost 2 kilos this week, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad. So I&amp;rsquo;m now at 102 kg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t work on my master thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really disappointed with my progress. I lacked the discipline to work on the things that matter the most. The things that will make my life better. Here&amp;rsquo;s where I think I failed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not working when I&amp;rsquo;m feeling down or tired - This happens a lot. If I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling okay, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard for me to do whatever. Gotta learn how to brush small issues off, and work on what&amp;rsquo;s important, whether I feel like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lack of focus - I can&amp;rsquo;t do anything for 10 minutes straight without going on reddit at least once. Gotta work on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major lessons learned this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thoughts are important. I should strive to always have the best possible thoughts and mental state. However, my mental state and thoughts tend to be average / bad. Very rarely do I find myself truly motivated. So I gotta be able to get things done, regardless of my mental state. This is SUPER hard. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things I hear people say a lot&amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t think most people can pull this off. So I gotta pay very close attention to my thoughts and mental state, but don&amp;rsquo;t rely on them entirely to get things done. One way to accomplish this is by asking myself &amp;ldquo;Can I do X right now?&amp;rdquo;, and answer with a number ranging from 1 to 10. 1 means I absolutely cannot do X right now. 10 means I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely motivated to do task X right now. If the answer is between 1-3, it&amp;rsquo;s best to just take a short break.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just focus on doing a certain task. Focus on doing the task CORRECTLY. e.g. if you want to write an article, don&amp;rsquo;t just focus on creating the article. Take time to review what you write. Ask yourself &amp;ldquo;Is this the best thing I should be doing right now?&amp;rdquo;. Take short breaks every 50 minutes or so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just tell yourself what you gotta do, over and over again, and hope to eventually get anything done. Instead, make a plan. Focus on doing the very first task of that plan. This first task should be a small one. This way, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to get the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ll probably forget about all this in the morning. SEE YA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey Week 0/26</title>
      <link>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jongomez.github.io/post/journey0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is the beginning of my 6 month (26 weeks) journey. The goal of this journey is to sell stuff online. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to focus on selling wordpress plugins and services, even though I have 0 experience with PHP. I also have 0 experience with wordpress. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on my master thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to loose some weight. I currently weigh 104 kilos, or 230 pounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lifting weights for about 3 years now, so some of that weight is muscle. But I&amp;rsquo;m also fat. Which sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, March 10th of 2017, was the 1st day of my journey. It was a terrible day for me. Another day wasted on reddit. One may argue that being on reddit is not wasting time, but in my case, I think it is. There were other things I wish I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not fair for me to say &amp;ldquo;I wish I wasn&amp;rsquo;t on reddit&amp;rdquo;, because something in my head clearly &amp;ldquo;wished&amp;rdquo; to be on reddit. A more correct statement would be &amp;ldquo;a part of me wished I was not on reddit&amp;rdquo;. This is the part of me that actually cares about me. The part of me that wants me to survive, and to excel, and to live a great life. With this journey, I hope to work on this part of myself, making it stronger, while slowly weakening the opposing, lazy part of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be making weekly blog posts updates on my journey. I&amp;rsquo;m posting this on my blog to keep me on track, while simultaneously hoping that someone, somewhere, will follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>